I'd like you to close your eyes and take a moment to focus on your breathing with curiosity.
And then for a moment, bring into your mind's eye your feet.
I often think that our feet are our hidden warriors, your feet, your beautiful feet that
take you on vacations. Feet that when you are alone in bed go up against the soft cloth,
or feet that may be reached out to another person's feet. Your feet that have carried
you into situations where you've been scared. See if you can think of some of those. And
when we do this, keep in mind that some people think in technicala and some people think
and do these kinds of exercises in a very way that is fuzzy. Either is okay. See if you
can let go of trying to do this exercise right and see if you can just be. Feet that have
walked you into a hospital where you've maybe bought a child into the world. Feet that have
walked you onto an airplane to say goodbye to people that you love. And now gradually think of
your feet getting smaller, smaller and smaller, more tender. And gradually think of those feet
wearing a pair of childhood shoes. Shoes that you may be used to wear as a child. See if you can
bring up the details of those. And again, if nothing comes to mind you can just make something up.
This is an exercise in imagination. Now I'd like you to search facts through your memories to a time
when you remember feeling a little sad or lonely or frightened or shamed. Perhaps when you were six
or seven. Maybe a little older or a little younger. Picture what you look like at that age.
Imagine how small your hands were and the type of clothing you wore.
Perhaps imagine yourself in one of your favourite artfuls.
Now put yourself in the place of this child as if you have become the child.
You are looking at the world through the child's eyes. Look down. You are now the child and you're
seeing small hands and the clothes that you're wearing. Now imagine that you're going back to the
place where you lived when you were that age. If you can't picture your exact home at that age,
choose one that you can picture.
Once you have the image, imagine that you are standing before the home as that child.
Imagine walking to the front door and reaching up to take the door knob,
turning it to open the door and slipping through.
Look around and notice the pictures on the walls, the furniture. Notice that you have to look
up to see some things given how small you are.
Now, I'd like you to go to the place in your home where you might find your wise person.
It might be your mother or mother figure. It might be a father or father figure.
It could be a teacher, a relative, a sibling, a friend,
someone who you know looks out for you and wants the best for you.
When you have found the person, notice what the person is doing.
Look around and see the room.
Walk up to your wise person and do whatever you have to do to get that person's attention.
So that that person looks you right in the face.
They see not only your face, but they see that eyes behind your eyes.
The soul in your soul.
Once they look at you from that place,
then from the position of your early hurt, tell the person what it is that you need.
Tell her or him tell them what it is you need, maybe it's love or kindness,
understanding, forgiveness, nurturing acceptance.
Just notice what it's like or another person just to be present with you.
See if you can stay with a simple reality that there is another person over there looking at you.
See if you can let go of your sense of wanting to do this right.
Now gently pull away from the person and begin to walk to the front door.
When you arrive, reach up and turn the knob to open the door.
Remember again that you are small.
You step through and you pull the door behind you.
You begin to walk away from the house.
Heading down the sidewalk of the street.
And as you do this, notice that in the distance you see someone walking towards you.
As the person gets closer, you see that it is an adult walking towards you.
And as you get closer, you realise that it is you.
It is the adult you you are today.
Go up to the adult that you see before you.
You are now the little child and you are seeing the adult version of you in front of you.
Do whatever you have to do to get that person's attention.
So that the adult version of you looks the child version of you right in the face.
Once you have that person's attention from the place of hurt, ask for what you need.
The child version of you right now is asking the adult version of you for what you need.
And now as the adult, tell the child what you need from her.
Now imagine you are leaving the scene of meeting the adult you on the sidewalk.
And if you transport it back to this very moment, to this room, to this chair,
you are now the adult that you know today.
Now imagine that the little child, the child you were just a moment ago is standing
right outside the door of this room.
The child is opening the door and stepping inside.
Imagine that the child is walking toward you and comes and stands right before you
and as they stand right before you give your attention.
Look the little child right in your eyes and see what the child needs.
And whatever the child asks for, give it to her, give it to him, give it to them.
This is an exercise in imagination you can give the child in front of you whatever it needs.
Notice if there is any withholding in you.
Check to see whether you are resisting anything.
And if so, see if you can let that go and give the child what it needs.
Tell the child that you are here and that you will help in any way you can.
If the child asks you to take him or her, then somewhere special go ahead and do it.
Offer a hug, a kiss, words of kindness.
This is an exercise in imagination.
And if the younger child doesn't know what he or she wants or doesn't trust you,
let them know that that is fine, that you are here for support and will help in whatever way you can.
Now imagine that the child is climbing into your left,
is melting into you, becoming a part of you.
Continue to radiate caring and kindness towards the younger you in any way you can.
Once you have a sense that this younger you has accepted, you're caring in your kindness.
Let the child be, bring awareness to your breathing
and bring yourself back when you are ready.